Arnaud TAFFO



I have seven years of experience in information technology among which four in finance and investment banking. Having worked as an application support analyst on trading applications my curiosity pushed me to discover the other side of the picture. So I have recently developed a strong interest for web development and I spend some of my free time learning web technologies and working on web projects.

FUNCTIONAL SKILLS

Skill Areas Web development, responsive web design, application support, user support,

maintenance of systems, software quality assurance, incident management, task automation, deployment in production, collect of needs, writing of functional

specifications, production of reports

Methodology ITIL, problem solving skills, analytical skills, initiative, communication, team work

A, TECHNICAL SKILLS

Environments Windows, Unix

Databases SQL, Oracle, SQL Server

Web HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Node.is

Programming PowerShell,, Java, C#, VBA

Software Oracle SQL Developer, SQL Server Management Studio, Windows PowerShell ISE,

Autosys, Dollar Universe, FileZilla, HP Quality Center, Microsoft Office

₩ WOR

WORK EXPERIENCE

CGI, Application Support Analyst. At Societe Generale Corporate and Investment Banking (SGCIB) - Montreal Solution Center (MSC)

2014 - 2018 Montreal, Canada

Money Market / Loan and Borrowing / Trading Application / Front-to-Back Office

In charge of stabilizing the production on a Front-to-Back Office trading application dedicated to the loan and borrowing activity on the money market. The application serves as a refinancing universal system: trade booking, validation workflow, confirmations, payment notices, accounting

- Provide technical and functional support to users for America, Europe and Asia regions
- · Automate daily routine tasks
- Manage production incidents
- · Collect business needs and requirements
- · Participate in process improvement
- Produce audit/regulatory reports
- Communicate with all the stakeholders (users, development team, infrastructure team)
- Participate to the transformation project to migrate the existing application to a new system software to improve performance and increase the level of security through new controls implemented
- · Monitor the migrated processes in production
- Assist users on new features

Technologies: Unix, Windows, PowerShell, SQL, Oracle Database, Oracle SQL Developer, Citrix, Autosys, \$Universe, FileZilla, Jira

Sopra Steria, Quality Assurance Analyst. At BNP Paribas

Electronic Banking / Automated Teller Machines

Paris, France

2013 - 2014

In charge of the quality assurance of new software versions installed on automated teller machines

- Run the tests and update the test books
- Analyze and monitor anomalies
- Install on pilot sites and monitor pilots
- · Provide support to banking agencies

Technologies: Windows, Unix, HP Quality Center

Sopra Steria, Analyst. At SFR (French telecommunication company)

2012

Redesign project of SFR information system

Paris, France

- · Install and maintain SFR environments
- · Write functional specifications about simulators of application systems involved in a customer subscription
- Run performance tests

Technologies: Unix, Korn Shell

Sopra Steria, Analyst. Specifications and development

2011

Capital market software Back/Middle Office

Paris, France

- · Write functional specifications about option pricing models
- Correct anomalies
- Develop an option pricing module

Technologies: Microsoft.NET

EDUCATION

2006 - 2011 Graduate school of engineering - ESILV Paris, France Master degree in financial engineering

Mathematics applied to finance



CERTIFICATION

2015 ITIL (Foundation level)

IT service management best practices Montreal, Canada



LANGUAGES

French Mother tongue

English Full professional proficiency

Basic notions **Spanish**



HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Project: creation of a responsive online resume with the front-end technologies such as HTML5, CSS3 and

JavaScript (URL: https://arnaud-taffo.github.io)

Sport: member of Societe Generale soccer team in corporate league

Travels, music, personal development